（华纳兄弟影业公司出品）
（1973年夏）
迈克尔？
Michael?
你在外面干什么呢，儿子？都后半夜了
What are you doing out here, son? It's after midnight.
我睡不着，爸爸
Couldn't sleep, Pops.
我们也睡不着，都是被你吵的
Well, neither can we, with all that noise you're making.
来吧，回屋去睡吧
Come on, let's go inside.
再投一个？
Just one more shot?
好吧 只投一个
All right. Just one.
好球 再来一个
That's good. Shoot it again.
越来越准了，儿子
Getting pretty good, son.
继续，看你能连进几个
Go ahead, shoot till you miss.
你觉得如果我球打得好，能进大学吗？
You think if I can get good enough, I can go to college?
只要能打好球，美梦都会成真，迈克尔
if you get good enough, you can do anything you want to, Michael.
我想去北卡罗莱纳
I want to play at North Carolina.
那是个好学校 很好的学校
That's a real fine school. Real fine school.
在那儿你会得到第一流的教育
You can get a first-class education there.
我要打进一支大学冠军队
I want to play on a championship team.
然后我想到NBA打球
Then I want to play in the NBA.
好吧，慢慢来，孩子
All right, let's slow down, son.
首先你是不是应该考虑去睡觉了呢？
Don't you think you ought to get a little sleep first?
一旦我打完篮球…
And once I've done all that...
我就去打棒球，像你一样，爸爸
I want to play baseball, just like you, Dad.
棒球，是了不起的运动
Baseball. Now, that's a sport.
当你打完棒球之后
And when you're finished with that,
我猜你还要去遨游太空，对吗？
I suppose you're gonna fly, huh?
片名：空中大掼蓝
（莱尼中学）
我觉得在这个特殊时刻…
I just feel at this particular time...
我的篮球生涯已达到顶峰，我该激流勇退了
that I reached the, uh, pinnacle of my basketball career and I must retire.
让我感到安慰的一件美好事情
The one good thing that comes out of this
就是我的父亲能有机会…
is that my father had the opportunity...
看到我最后一场告别比赛，这对我很重要
to see me play my last basketball game, and that means a lot to me.
你今后打算做什么？
What are you gonna do now?
我从来没跟外界透露过，除了一个人…
Well, I've never really told anybody this, except for one person, and, uh...
我打算参加职业棒球队
But I think I'm gonna go play professional baseball.
你将要打什么位置？
What position will you play?
还没想好 小时候，我当过投手
I don't know. As a kid, I was a pitcher.
我不适合当投手
I think that would be kind of hard for me to pitch,
那我想当外野手
so I'm gonna play the outfield.
（游乐园）
（莫伦山）
（污泥顶）
我们走吧，爸爸 这里让人讨厌
Let's get out of here, Dad. This stinks.
别再带我来这里了，好吗？
Don't bring me here anymore, all right?
别再带我来这里了，好吗？你在听吗？
Don't bring me here anymore, all right? Are you listening?
你们听见了没有？
Did you hear him?
那小家伙说得没错
That little brat is right.
我跟你们说过，如果曾经跟你们说过…
I've told you, if I've told you once...
我跟你们说过不止一次，一百万次，一千万次！
I told you a thousand, thousand, thousand, thousand times.
我们需要新节目
We need new attractions.
- 没错 - 新花样
- Right. - New ones.
- 明白吗？ - 热闹非凡的新节目
- Get it? - Big, shiny new things, yeah.
- 一点儿不错，老板 - 看着我 都给我听着
- Absolutely, sir. - Look at me. Look at me and listen.
顾客永远是对的
The customer is always right.
- 明白  - 顾客永远是对的
- Right. - The customer is always right.
完全正确
Exactly.
永远
Always.
明白
Right.
- 我们需要某种… - 我的错
- Okay, we need something... - My bad.
我们需要某种…
We need something...
- …刺激 - 刺激
- ...nutty. - Nutty.
- 古怪的事 - 古怪
- Something wacky. Wacky.
我们需要某种…
We need something, something... Something... We need something...
乐你通？
Looney?
乐你通 谢谢
Looney. Thank you.
乐你通？
Looney?
我是一只麋鹿 朝我开枪吧
I'm an elk. Shoot me.
太好了，乐你通
Yes. Looney. Yes.
现在是你说的 乐你通 乐你通 就是这样
Now you're talking. Looney. Looney. That's it.
我要的就是这个东西 乐你通
That's the word I was looking for. Looney.
- 去把乐你通弄来  - 乐你通！
- Get the Looney Tunes. - Looney Tunes!
- 带他们来 - 注意看着
- Bring them here. Sir. Just noticing, sir.
他们在地球 要是不肯来怎么办？
They're from Earth. What if they can't come?
你说什么？他们不肯来？
What did you say? What if they can't come?
- 抓他们来 - 好
- Make them. - Cool.
抓他们来
Make them.
我们去抓他们
We're gonna go get them.
好球！
Strike!
他穿上球衣很有风度
Looks good in that uniform.
风度翩翩 天生的
Looks great. Can't teach that.
天生的
Can't teach it.
谢谢你在我儿子的棒球上签名 我可是英雄了
Thanks for autographing that basketball for my kid. I'm a hero now.
没问题 我很愿意这样做
No problem. Happy to do it, man.
开始！
Let's go!
曲线球 不要接
Curve ball. Don't swing.
不要接
Don't swing.
坏球！
Ball!
快球，偏外球，快打
Fastball, outside corner. Swing.
好球！
Strike!
多好的机会
That was your pitch.
知道，没打着
I know, I missed it.
别着急 我让他再来一次
Don't worry. I'll get you another one.
波拉克 波拉克，到这儿来
Podolak. Podolak, come here.
对不起，我本来…
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
- 来一下 - 什么事？
- Come here. - Yes, sir?
确保迈克尔不受任何打扰
Make sure nobody bothers Michael.
我要让他成为最开心的球员
I want him to be the happiest player in the world.
最开心的
The happiest.
斜线快球 不打
Slider. Don't swing.
三击不中！
Strike three!
我叫你不要打
I told you not to swing.
我忍不住
I couldn't help it.
我明白，很高兴见到你
I understand. Hey, nice talking to you.
我们不着急 我们不着急
We're not worried. We're not worried.
干得好，迈克尔 很好的进攻
Good job, Mike. Good hustle.
切入不错，迈克尔 切入不错
Good cut, Michael. Good cut.
一次三次不中出局吗？漂亮的出局 真的漂亮
That was a strikeout, Mike? Good-looking strikeout. Real good.
你的出局动作也好看
You look good when you strike out.
我出局时的动作糟糕透顶
When I strike out, it looks nasty, man.
至少你的姿势很好看，很好看的
At least you look good, man. Good-looking.
嗨，乔丹先生
Hi, Mr. Jordan.
我是斯坦・波拉克…
Mr. Jordan, I'm Stan Podolak...
天哪
Oh, jeez.
- 你没事吧？ 摔得够不轻 - 是的
- You all right? That was a nasty fall. - Yeah.
我叫斯坦・波拉克，新来的公关先生
Oh. I'm Stan Podolak, Mr. Jordan. I'm the Barons' new publicist.
专门让你轻松愉快，要不要为你开车兜风？
I'm here to make your life easier. Want me to drive you somewhere?
要不要为你洗衣服、替你看孩子？我都会做
Want me to pick up your laundry, babysit your kids? I will do it.
我在这里当面向你保证，没人敢来打扰你
I am here to personally guarantee that no one will ever bother you.
这算什么？
What was that?
坐稳了
Hang on.
- 别乱动  - 扶好
- Hanging on. - Hanging on.
怎么还没到？
Are we there yet?
- 太刺激了！ - 噢！
- Bombastic. - Cool.
讨厌的兔巴哥
All right, you irascible bunny.
回来，你这个疯疯颠颠的家伙
Come back here, you screwy rodent.
我马上就过来找你的，伙计们
I'll, uh, be with you in a second, folks,
我先去对付那个野小子
after I finish with nature boy here.
你这烦人的兔子 这回我抓住你了
All right, you pesky rabbit. I've got you now.
对我来说是一小步…
One small step for moi...
对莫伦山来讲是巨大的飞跃（Moron有笨蛋的意思）
One giant leap for Moron Mountain.
埃尔默・福特遇上了大麻烦
And one whopper headache for Elmer Fudd.
他们小得可怜，是不是？
Diminutive, ain't they?
- 我们在找一只叫兔巴哥的兔子 - 是的，叫兔巴哥
- We seek the one they call Bugs Bunny. - Yeah, Bugs Bunny.
- 见过他吗？ - 他在哪？
- Have you seen him? - Where is this guy?
是不是在附近？
Is he around?
兔巴哥，兔巴哥
Bugs Bunny, Bugs Bunny.
他是不是有一对长耳朵？
Say, does he have, uh, great big long ears?
- 像我一样？ - 是的 是的
- Like this? - Yeah. Yeah.
是不是像这样跳来跳去？
And does he hop around like this?
- 是的 - 那个…
- Yeah. - Well, uh...
他说“怎么回事，先生？”是不是这样：
does he say, "What's up, doc?" Like this:
- 怎么回事，先生？ - 是的！
- Eh, what's up, doc? - Yeah!
没有 没见过它
Nope. Never heard of him.
其它星球上不可能存在智能生物
You know, maybe there is no intelligent life out there in the universe after all.
给我站住，乐你通先生
Hold on there, Mr. Looney Tune.
你把我们当傻瓜吗？
Hey, what do you think we are, stupid?
老实呆着
Don't move a muscle.
兔巴哥，把你的伙伴们集合起来
Okay, bunny, gather up your Tune pals.
- 咱们去旅行    - 快点
- We're taking you for a ride. - Move it, mister.
一个不剩，我们去哪里？
Totally. All right. So, like, where are we going?
还没到吗？
Are we there yet?
- 对不起，耽误你不少时间 - 没关系
- Sorry it took so long. - Don't worry.
找不到65号公路的出口 等等，就这儿
That exit wasn't clearly marked. Hold up, right here.
- 停在这里？ - 是的
- What, here?   - Yes.
谢谢，史尔 非常感谢
Thanks for the ride, Sherm. Appreciate it.
- 我叫斯坦 - 抱歉
- It's Stan, Mike. - Sorry.
你高兴叫我史尔也行
But you can call me Sherm if you want to.
我是你的追星族
I've followed your whole career.
- 我认为你是世界上最棒的球员 - 斯坦，斯坦，斯坦
- You're the greatest athlete that's ever lived. - Stan, Stan, Stan.
我怎么出去？车门打不开
How do I get out? The door doesn't work.
- 对不起 我忘了… 这是古董车 - 是啊
- I'm sorry. I forgot... It's a classic. - Oh, yeah.
是古董车，就是常闹点小毛病 稍等
It's a classic, but it's got a few peccadilloes. Hold on just a second.
小毛病？发动机都冒烟了 你需要去检查一下
A few, huh? It's smoking, too, man. You need to get that checked.
谢谢你送我回来
Thanks for the ride.
真不错，这房子真不错
Oh, this is nice. This is a nice house.
太漂亮了，是殖民时期风格？
That is a beauty. What is that, Colonial?
是座好房子
It's a nice house.
如果你需要帮手，我会很乐意…
If you need anything done around the house, I'd be happy...
- 哦，不，我能对付，谢谢 - 任何你需要的
- Oh, no, I'm fine, thanks. - Anything you need.
- 你送我回来 我非常感谢 - 没事
- You gave me a ride. I appreciate it. - Sure.
明天早上我开车好吗？不用你来接了
Tomorrow I'm gonna drive, okay? So I don't need the ride.
再次谢谢
But thanks, though.
是不是太显眼了？
Too conspicuous?
是
Yeah.
- 好吧 好吧 - 还是要谢谢你
- All right. All right. - Thanks, though.
- 明天见   - 明天见
- Tomorrow. - See you tomorrow.
别这样，今天就免了吧
Come on, dog. No, not today.
快走开！臭烘烘的！
Dog, get off me. Your breath.
- 乔丹先生，你没事吧？ - 放开我！
- Mr. Jordan, are you okay? - Get off of me!
放开他，查尔斯
Get off of him, Charles.
- 坏蛋，走开 - 放开他
- Bad dog. Git. - Get off of him.
- 放开我，查尔斯 - 放开他不然我要揍你
- Get off me, Charles. - Get off of him before I cook you.
跟我来，宝贝儿
Come on, come on. Come on, baby. Come on.
下车啦！
Get out of the car!
打得不错
Good game.
杰夫，怎么啦？
Hey, Jeff, you okay?
- 比赛怎么样？ - 我不想谈这事
- How was your game? - I don't want to talk.
你好，爸爸
Hi, Dad.
迈克尔！
Michael!
- 爸爸，爸爸！ - 你好吗？
- Daddy, Daddy! - How you doing?
- 你怎么一脸口水？ - 都是你的狗
- You're all covered with drool, baby. - That's your dog.
- 杰夫怎么了？ - 他丢了2到5个…
- What's wrong with Jeff? - He went two for five...
- 他丢了32个球 - 就是这些吗？
- lost 32 points in his average. - Is that all?
他的命中率是千分之六八五
Yeah, so that puts him at like a.685 or something.
他打什么？
He's batting what?
好香啊，你在做什么？
Smells good in here. What you cooking?
- 炖鸡 - 鸡和什么？
- Chicken. - Chicken and what?
- 鸡肉和莴苣   - 好极了 我需要有营养的晚餐
- Chicken and collard greens. - Good. I'm gonna need a good meal tonight.
一切都好吗？
Is everything okay?
糟糕透了 但愿我玩棒球这种运动是个好想法
I stunk up the place. I hope this baseball thing was a good idea.
这是迈克尔・乔丹另一职业生涯的第一天，在贵族球场的下午
It was another career day for Michael Jordan at Barons Field this afternoon.
拭目以待吧 这种棒球…
Let's face it. This baseball...
他们在看什么？
What are you guys watching?
- 他打了3个三击不中 - 不能看点儿别的吗？
- Today he had three strikeouts. - Is this the only thing on TV?
- 让他的平均击中率下降到… - 这是什么啊？
- That brings his batting average down... - What's up with this?
千分之214，恰好是他的体重
to an anemic.214, which is also his weight.
球棒？也许该给他换只网球拍子
Baseball bat? Get this guy a tennis racquet.
球友们都对你很气愤？
Did everyone get mad at you?
不，还要糟 他们一个劲地夸我
No. Worse. Everyone was real nice about it.
迈克尔，我知道你高尔夫打得不错，但不是这里
Michael, I know golf is your sport, but not here.
我觉得你应该把站位打开一点
I think you should open up your stance a little.
那样会让你在本垒板上更有侵略性
It might make you more aggressive at the plate.
是这样吗？我会记住
You think so? I'll try to remember that.
看似我比你还难过
Watching this hurts me more than you.
干嘛要看这种节目？对你不好
What are you guys doing watching this stuff? It's bad for you.
这个好 公路奔跑者 看哔哔鸟
There you go. Road Runner. Beep, beep.
今天就到这
Stop this cartoon.
我们要去参加卡通工会召开的紧急会议
We've got an emergency Cartoon Character Union Meeting to go to.
慢点，等等我 不要着急
Hey, wait for me. Hold your horses.
他们去哪里了？
Dang. Where'd they go?
- 关掉音乐 - 大活鸭大驾光临
- Stop the music. - Top duck coming through.
连个澡也不让人洗痛快
Jeez. It's getting so a guy can't even get himself wet around here.
什么事这么着急？
So, what's the big emergency?
这些小东西要宣布一件事 开始吧，少说点
Uh, these little guys would like to make an announcement. Here you go, shorty.
- 说吧 - 好吧，好吧
- Go. - All right, all right.
你们已经成了我们的俘虏
You, all of you, are now our prisoners.
这回可麻烦了
We're in big trouble now.
我们要带你们去太空中的游乐园
We are taking you to our theme park in outer space.
- 是真的 - 你们将成为我们的奴隶
- No fooling. - Where you'll be our slaves.
还要公开展出供我们的付费游客观赏
And placed on display for the amusement of our paying customers.
太可怕了
Oh, fear clutches my breast.
我们哪也不去
We ain't going nowheres.
先别着急
Eh, not so fast, doc.
我们不能束手就擒，这不公平
You just can't turn us into slaves. That would be bad.
该给我们一自卫的机会
You've gotta give us a chance to defend ourselves.
是吗？谁说的？说谁的？
Oh, yeah? Who says? Says who?
- 为何？ - 等一下
- Why?    - Just a sec.
- 这个读一下并哭泣吧 - 这是什么？
- There. Read them and weep. - What's this?
“要给对方以自卫反抗的机会”
"Give them a chance to defend themselves."
一定要给？
Do we have to?
- 规则书上讲的 - 这是规则
- It's in the rule book. - It is.
好吧 规则书上讲的
Okay. It is in the rule book.
我们商量一下
We have to confer.
好吧将士们 我们必须选择一个对我们有利的战场…
All right, troops. It is for us to choose a battlefield that affords us...
我有个主意
Oh, I got it.
什么主意，猪小胖？
Yes, Private Porkster?
跟他们玩个…拼字游戏怎么样？
How about we challenge them to a...spelling bee?
最好是保龄球比赛
Say...we could have a bowling tournament.
一群蠢才
Suffering succotash.
你们怎么搞的？
What's wrong with all of you?
我说咱们找个梯子…
I say we get a ladder...
一直等到那个老奶奶一出门…
wait till the old lady's out of the room...
一把抓住那只鸟
then grab that little bird.
哇哦，你还是歇会儿吧
Whoa, whoa, take a deep breath, Sly.
还是先分析一下敌情
Okay, let's analyze the competition.
目前看到的情况是什么？
Now, uh, what are we looking at here?
我们看到一群外星入侵者
We got a small race of invading aliens.
短胳膊，短腿
Small arms. Short legs.
跑得不快
Not very fast.
身材很矮小
Tiny little guys.
跳得也不高
Can't jump high.
我们决定和你们比赛打篮球
We challenge you to a basketball game.
打篮球就打篮球
All right. Basketball it is.
- 打篮球  - 打篮球
- Basketball. - Basketball.
什么是篮球？
What is basketball?
- 是什么？ - 不知道
- What's that? - Beats me.
我们在学校都没见过
We didn't have that in school.
- 关灯 - 对不起，让我过去
- Lights. - Pardon me. Sorry.
前面的坐下
Down in front.
一个振奋人心的团队运动…
An exhilarating team sport...
风靡一时，这就是篮球
currently growing rapidly in popularity is basketball.
与足球和棒球不同的是
Unlike football and baseball,
每队只有5名队员上场参赛
only five men can play on a team.
它的节奏很快，令人眼花缭乱，需要有敏捷的思维…
It's a fast-paced, razzle-dazzle game that requires quick wits...
和更快的反应
and even faster reflexes.
具有专业级别的…
Here's how it's done in the professional ranks...
美国职业篮球联合会
the National Basketball Association,
以拥有世界最优秀球员为特征
featuring the best players in the world.
- 世界最优秀的球员 - 最优秀的
- The best players in the world. - The best.
（纽约市）
借光 哦，对不起
Excuse me. Oh, so sorry.
抱歉
Excuse me.
不要踢我鼻子
Get your feet out of my nose.
小声点，有人在看我们
Quiet, they're looking.
这就是篮球
Hey, it's basketball.
在哪？下边干什么？
Where? Whoa. Now what?
怎么啦？
What?
- 她在看我们 - 快挡好
- She's looking again. - Close it up.
挡紧一些
Tightly.
你又在捅我
You poked me again.
- 亲爱的？ - 什么？
- Sweetheart? - What?
你该找个好点的座位
I thought you'd get better seats.
这已经是能找到最好的了
This is as good as I could get.
我旁边这人穿着雨衣表现得怪里怪气的
This guy next to me is doing something very weird in his raincoat.
宝贝，让我好好看球赛行吗？巴克利杀得太狠了
Honey, will you just let me watch the game? Barkley's killing us.
有人杀人了
Hey, someone's killing someone.
不 严重吗？
No. Seriously?
哇哦，凶手 让我看看
Wow, a killer. Let me see.
那里 就是他，杀手
There. That's him, the killer.
个子高
He's big.
球技好
He's good.
他是我的了
He's mine.
快去抓他
Okay, go get him. Yeah.
快回去防守 快回去 回防，伙计
Get back on defense. Let's go. Get back on defense, man.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
暂停 请求暂停
Time out. Call time out.
你这是怎么了？你在毁掉比赛
What's wrong with you, man? You're killing us.
- 让我进去 快打开 - 打开
- Let him in. Open up. - Open.
他成功了
He did it.
得到了 我得到了他的球技
I got it. I got his talent.
- 好的 - 太棒了
- All right. - Super.
- 坐下，查尔斯  - 我很好，我没事
- Sit down, Chuck. - Man, I'm fine. I am fine.
不，不 我给了你太多上场时间
No, no. I played you too many minutes.
- 但我不累  - 去叫医生
- But I'm not tired. - Go get the doctor.
- 怎么了伙计？你没事吧？ - 没事
- What's up, man? You all right? - Yeah.
真的？
You sure?
来吧，我没事，你没事 我们接着打
Come on, we're okay. You're okay. Come on, let's go.
帕特里克，该比赛了
Come on, Patrick. It's showtime.
他怎么了？
What's wrong with him?
爆米花…
Popcorn...
一个令人震惊的新情况…
In a shocking development...
五名NBA球员在过去24小时都被列入了伤病名单中…
five NBA players have been placed on the disabled list in the last 24 hours...
他们都是患了同一种怪病
all suffering from the same mysterious ailment.
- 什么？ - 不管内幕是什么…
- Yeah? Hmm. - Whatever this mystery is...
它严重影响球员协调性
it affects the player's coordination.
我过几天就回家
I'll be home in a couple days.
- 看看帕特里克・尤因 - 让妈妈听电话
- Watch Patrick Ewing. - Put your mom on the phone.
- 不仅仅是在纽约 - 宝贝 你好吗？
- It wasn't just in New York. - Hey, baby. How you doing?
- 看看这重要新闻 - 你在看电视？
- Check out the highlights. - You watching TV?
到底是怎么了？
What the hell is going on?
你没事吧？
You gonna be all right?
我好了，教练 没关系
I'm ready, coach. All right.
看来我退的正是时候
Looks like I retired just in time.
好吧，我得走了
All right, baby, gotta go.
回头再给你打电话，我爱你，再见
I'll call you later, okay? Love you. Bye.
门没锁！
It's open!
该上场了 穿好你的恒适内衣和耐克鞋
Come on, it's game time. Get your Hanes on. Lace up your Nikes.
拿上威帝和佳得乐饮料
Grab your Wheaties and your Gatorade
路上再买个大汉堡
and we'll pick up a Big Mac on the way.
再来看看洛杉矶赛场的情况
Now we take you live to the Forum in Los Angeles...
湖人队的球员拒绝进场比赛
where the Lakers are refusing to take the court.
伙计们，换上球衣
Guys, we gotta get dressed.
我们5分钟后上场
We got a game in five minutes.
我是在说一大笔的罚金
I mean, we're talking about a huge fine here.
不，我们不能进更衣室
No, we can't go in the locker room.
你知道是什么害了巴克利和尤因？ 听说那儿有病毒
You heard what happened to Barkley and Ewing. There's germs in there.
赛德里克，那可是在纽约，离这里3千英里
Cedric, that was in New York, 3000 miles away.
这种病毒的传播速度比光速快
Bacteria can travel faster than the speed of light.
- 就像电影“人体入侵者”一样   - 是的，应该是
- It could be Invasion of the Body Snatchers. Yeah, could be.
好啦 在走廊里换
All right. Dress in the hallway.
好
Okay.
好好，你们这些人当中有谁曾经打过篮球？
Okay, okay, now, which one of you maroons has ever played basketball before?
我打过，教练 不过有个重要问题我必须得问问你
I have, coach. And there's an important strategic question I need to ask you.
什么问题？
Yes, yes?
你觉得怎么样？我比较偏好穿紫色和金黄色球衣（湖人队服）
What do you think? I'm kind of partial to purple and gold, myself.
那样会很搭配我的肤色 一二三四
It goes better with my coloring. A one, two, three, four.
很漂亮，达菲鸭
Guys? Nice outfit, Daffy.
那些小东西说该他们使用场地
The little aliens say it's their turn to, uh, use the court.
好吧，让这些小人物把自己活活累死
Sure, let the little pipsqueaks knock themselves out.
可惜他们不能让自己长的再高些，伙计们
Too bad you can't practice getting taller, boys.
嗨，猪小胖
Hey, little pig.
我的裤子湿了
I wet myself.
该我们玩这个小球了
Time to play a little basketball.
那些小东西怎么成了超级球星？
Those little pipsqueaks just turned into superstars.
他们都是魔鬼球星
They're monsters.
Suffering succotash.
是魔鬼球星
They're Monstars.
再见
Bye-bye.
看来我们需要外援
Eh, I think we might need a little bit of help.
一百七十五码
A hundred and seventy-five yards.
小东西，你是我的朋友还是我的敌人？
Okay, little fella. You my friend or are you my enemy?
你是我朋友，对吗？你是我的搭档
You are my friend, right? You are my ally.
你是我的助手，我的私人助理
You are my associate, my personal assistant.
你是我的武器 你躲过去了
You are my weapon. You are leaving.
- 好极了 - 打得不错，莫里先生
- Great shot. - Nice shot, Mr. Murray.
你的手可以放下来了
You can stop posing now.
- 相当好  - 不错，不错啊
- Good try. - Not bad, not bad.
- 够你们学一阵的 - 好好打
- Something for you to shoot at. - Hit it good.
尽量吧
Do my best.
打得漂亮
It was a good shot.
当然
Yeah, I know.
问你件事
Mike, I gotta ask you something.
NBA必须面对现实
The NBA has to face reality.
现在这些球员的情况很严重
What's happening to these players is serious.
得重新物色有天赋的新球员
They're gonna need new players with talent.
受过训练的，但之前从没想过要当职业球员的家伙
Guys who are skilled, but never really thought about a professional career before.
你看我行吗？
You think I got a shot?
- 少来，行吗？ - 不
- Come on, really? - No.
- 别开玩笑  - 那是男人的运动
- Don't kid me. - Listen. It's a man's game.
- 你玩不了的 - 我要是努力点呢？
- You can't play. - What if I tried really hard?
小声点 我要击球了
Keep it down. I'm trying to hit this ball.
因为我是白人，是不是？
It's because I'm white, isn't it?
不，拉里也是白人 怎样？
No. Larry's white. So what?
拉里不是白人，他是仙人
Larry's not white. Larry's clear.
投得不错，拉里 很不错
Good shot, Larry. That's nice.
他的球要进洞了
Get inside his ball.
你们这些小丑是做不到的
You clowns can't beat that.
- 这是我的最高纪录 - 你才打过几次
- My best shot ever. - You haven't played long.
它将被载入史册
A Hall-of-Fame shot.
- 好球，伯德先生 - 叫我拉里好了
- Really nice shot, Mr. Bird. - Larry, please.
- 好球，拉里先生 - 打得不错，拉里
- Nice shot, Mr. Larry. - Nice shot, Larry.
你也能做到
You can do this.
不要紧张，你也能做到
Don't be nervous. You can do this.
拉里，你不认为NBA应当面对现实吗？
Larry, you feel that the NBA has to face reality, don't you?
应当在选人问题上眼界再开阔些
Gotta look for more dominant players in places they never looked before.
眼睛看着球 心里想着球的落点
Just look at the ball. Visualize where you want it to go.
- 对，对，对 - 看着球 看着球
- Right, right, right. - Be the ball. Be the ball.
你到外面去
Get off the tee.
弹跳差
You can't jump.
我… 说下去
I... Yeah, go on.
打赌吗？ 打赌吗？ 赌打午饭？
Close to the pin? Close to the pin? For dinner?
好主意 肯定我赢
Sounds good. I'll go close to the pin.
- 好的 - 我也参加
- Okay, cool. - I'll take some of that.
打得不错
That's not bad.
漂亮
Good shot.
下来呀
Get down.
瞧它有多美
Look at that. Look at that spin.
加油
Come on.
球会自己跑
It is alive.
好！好！这是我首次一杆入洞！
Yes! Yes! My first hole in one. Yes!
别说了 还是头一次看到
Don't say it. Never seen one of these before.
拉里，只要击打球底部就行
Larry, nothing but the bottom of the cup.
- 又让他占了先 - 非我莫属 抱歉
- That's his ball too. - Yeah, yeah, it's my ball. Sorry.
- 让我拍张照片  - 你在嫉妒
- Let me get a picture. - You guys are jealous.
一定要面带微笑
All right, here we go. Now, you gotta smile.
伸手掏球然后再微笑，好吗？
Reach in for the ball and then smile, okay?
- 是的 - 你在想，“感觉很好”
- Yes. - And you think, "This is good."
- 赶紧拍吧 - 好的
- Just take the picture. - Okay.
这相机搞什么鬼？
What kind of camera is that?
你不要把它对着我 关掉镜头盖
Don't point it at me. Close the lens cap.
- 我什么也没干 - 他去哪了？
- I didn't do anything. - Where did he go?
不不不！
No, no, no!
当心点，欢迎到乐你通
Oh, uh, look out for that first step, doc, it's a real lulu.
兔巴哥？
Bugs Bunny?
你以为我是复活节兔子？
Eh, you were expecting maybe the Easter Bunny?
- 你是卡通人物 你不是真的 - 不是真的？
- You're a cartoon. You're not real. - Not real, eh?
不是真的能干这个？
If I weren't real, could I do this?
瞧，这不是迈克尔吗？
Oh, look. Is that Michael?
是迈克尔
It's Michael.
是飞人乔丹
It's Air Jordan.
打篮球的
Basketball.
我看到了…
I tought I taw...
是的 我的确看到了迈克尔・乔丹
I did. I did see Michael Jordan.
打扰了，乔丹先生 你能为我…？
Pardon me, Mr. Jordan. Uh, can I have your auto...?
亲笔签名吗？
Your John Hancock, please?
退后 让鸭大夫瞧瞧
Back off. Let the doctor take a look.
- 高了点 - 不
- A little high. - No.
降下来
Going down.
不！
No!
（10分）
再转个身怎么样？
So, what do you say we go for a little spin?
看看里面都有什么？
Hmm. Now, let's see what we got inside here.
说“啊…”
Say "ah."
好了，他没毛病
All right. He's okay.
（一切正常）
- 怎么回事？ - 怎么，迈克尔，我以为你不会问
- What's going on here? - Why, Michael, I thought you'd never ask.
这些来外星来的小东西想让我们去游乐园当奴隶
These aliens from outer space want to make us slaves in their theme park.
怕他作甚？他们很小
What do we care? They're little.
那么我们和他们来一场篮球挑战赛
So we challenged them to a basketball game.
但是他们出现后并不是很小 他们都是巨人
But then they show up and they ain't so little. They're huge.
我们必须打败他们，因为他们想让我们做奴隶
We need to beat these guys, because they're talking about slavery.
他们会让我们表演单口相声
They'll make us do stand-up comedy,
每晚让我们天天讲同样的笑话
the same jokes every night for all eternity.
我们像野兽一样被锁链拖到台上演出…
We'll be locked up like wild animals and then trotted out to perform...
被一群没教养的、暴突眼的
for a bunch of lowbrow, bug-eyed,
肥头大耳的、缺乏幽默感的外星人取乐
fat-headed, humor-challenged aliens.
总而言之
Uh, what I'm trying to say is...
我们需要你的帮助
we need your help!
可我现在是棒球运动员
Yeah, but I'm a baseball player now.
没错，我是莎士比亚剧演员
Right. And I'm a Shakespearean actor.
迈克尔？迈克尔？我是斯坦 斯坦・波拉克
Mike? Michael? It's Stan. Stan Podolak.
请你马上出来，好吗？
Uh, look, I need you to come out now, okay?
你明天还有棒球比赛
Because you got a baseball game tomorrow.
你不出场，我实在交不了差
And I'd look pretty stupid if you don't show up.
觉得迈克尔没事吧？我不该扔下他
Think Michael's all right? I hate to leave him like this.
我确信他没事 他只是为了摆脱那个讨厌的斯坦
I'm sure he's fine. I think he just had to get away from that Stan character.
- 天啊，他怪可怜的，是不是？ - 是的
- God, he's pathetic, isn't he? - Yeah.
都算两杆进洞吧
I'm gonna give us both twos back there.
咱们都没有心情打下去了
We weren't in any kind of emotional state to putt.
- 这很公平 - 是的
- I think that's fair. - Yeah.
如果迈克尔不在，NBA就会另外找新人
Now, if Mike is gone, the NBA is gonna need some new people.
我对篮球情有独衷
There's room at the top.
令人兴奋的是中场休息还能客串节目
An exciting guy who could maybe even perform at half-time.
认识戴维・斯特恩吗？请你替我打个电话…
You still tight with David Stern? A phone call from you...
我很想帮你们，可我很久没摸篮球了
Look, I want to help, but I haven't played basketball in a long time.
- 我的时代已过去了 - 我们会帮你恢复
- My timing's all off. - Eh, we'll fix your timing.
看看我们的篮球设施
Look at our facilities.
我们有篮框
We've got hoops.
有举重器械
We got weights.
有篮球
We've got balls.
真不少 场地太乱了
You sure do. This place is a mess.
乱？你嫌场地太乱？
Mess? You're worried about a little mess?
我们的唾沫清洁法马上见效
There's nothing here a little spit shine wouldn't fix.
- 唾沫清洁！ - 唾沫清洁！
- Spit shine!   - Spit shine!
空气多么清新
Lemony-fresh.
简直是群疯子
You guys are nuts.
修订一下：我们是乐你通
Correction: We're Looney Tunes.
知识产权和注册商标属于华纳兄弟公司
And as such are the exclusive property and trademark of Warner Bros. Inc.
我来了
I'm here.
还有我
Me too.
好疼啊！
That hurt.
他们是谁？
Who are these guys?
记得我说过外星来的小东西？
Well, uh, remember the tiny aliens I told you about?
听说过“梦之队”？我们是“魔之队”，废物
You heard of the Dream Team? Well, we're the Mean Team, wussy-man.
- 废物 - 废物？
- Wussy-man. - Wussy-man?
我们是魔星之队
We're the Monstars.
看看你的本事，蠢货
Let's see what you got, chump.
我不打篮球了
I don't play basketball anymore.
“我不打篮球了”
"I don't play basketball anymore."
也许你是害怕了
Maybe you're chicken.
这话对我说还差不多
I say, I resemble that remark.
说我害怕？
You calling me chicken?
过来
Hey. Come here.
注意，接球
Here you go. Take him.
看我的步伐 是不是难以置信？
Watch the footwork. Can you believe it?
不要挡我上篮
Get out of the way.
你们看，这就是你们的篮球大英雄
Hey, everybody. Look at your hero now.
你们不要欺人太甚
You guys are making a big mistake.
你已经完蛋了，秃头
You're all washed up, baldy.
秃头？
Baldy?
你们肯定搞错了
He is not washed up.
- 迈克尔是最伟大的球星   - 住嘴
- Michael's the greatest ever. - Shut up.
我的小脑袋瓜
My poor little cranium.
- 你没事吧？ - 没事，你没事吧？
- You okay? - Yeah, are you okay?
你不怕他们，是不是，迈克尔？
You're not scared of them, are you, Michael?
我们来练球吧
Let's play some basketball.
Yeah, serve her! Come on! Rebound!
你是… 你是查尔斯・巴克利
You're... You're Charles Barkley.
姑娘们，快过来
Girls. Come on over. Hurry up. Hurry.
快看查尔斯・巴克利
Look. It's Charles Barkley.
一起玩好吗？
Hey, can I play?
你不是查尔斯・巴克利
You're not Charles Barkley.
只是个长得像他的可怜虫
Just a wannabe who looks like him.
没劲
Sorry. Break out.
你不该来这里 走开
You shouldn't even be here. Be gone.
冒牌货，走开
Wannabe. Be gone.
还需要做些检查
Just a few more tests, gentlemen.
化验电解质、葡萄糖、全血球、红血球等等
Electrolyte levels, glucose, CBCs, RBCs, etcetera.
还要做大运动量实验…
And we've scheduled a 12-lead stress test...
病理检查包括心电图、脑电图
and neurological battery to include EEG, reflex tests...
这姑娘，身高才5英尺，竟盖了我的帽
And this girl, 5-feet-nothing, blocked my shot.
这种幻觉什么时候开始的？
When did you first start having this dream?
这不是幻觉，是真的
It wasn't a dream. It really happened.
它爬上了我的后背钻进了我的大脑
And it climbed up my back and into my brain.
除了打篮球在做别的任何事情是…
Are there any other areas besides basketball...
你也感到力不从心吗？
where you find yourself unable to perform?
- 没有 - 随便问问
- No. - Just asking.
我做了B超、核磁共振、X光，全身扫描…
I've been MRI'd, EKG'd, x-rayed, laser beamed...
我保证再不骂裁判
I promise I'll never swear again.
再也不技术犯规
I'll never get another technical.
永远不说脏话
I'll never trash-talk.
我还会别的
I've got other skills.
- 我能回农场干活 - 真的？
- I could go back and work on the farm. - Really?
要不我就隐居山林再当一个修道士
Or maybe I could go back to the jungle and be a missionary again.
你说什么？只为不听妈妈的话？
What are you saying? That I'm trying to disobey my mama?
我没说 是你说的，马格斯
I didn't say that. You did, Muggsy.
我爱我母亲
But I love my mama.
还是查不出是么毛病
Still can't find anything wrong with us.
也许根本就没毛病
Hey, maybe nothing's wrong with us.
说的没错，马格斯 可能是脑袋出了问题
That's right, Muggs. Maybe it's just in our head.
我们没事 可能是某种精神紊乱
We're fine. It's just some psychosomatic deal.
也许和月亮有关系，或者是星球定位
Or something to do with the moon, or the alignment of the planet.
我再也不和麦当娜约会了
I'll never go out with Madonna again.
你干什么？
What are you doing?
我… 我在修整草坪
I'm, uh... I'm fixing a divot.
他在修草坪
He's fixing a divot!
（篮球选拔赛）
你们谁打过篮球？
Has anyone here ever played basketball?
我打过
Um, I have.
我想参加选拔赛
I'd like to try out for the team.
嗨，我是兔小妹罗拉
Hi. My name is Lola Bunny.
罗拉？
Lola?
你好 我是兔巴哥
Hello. Eh, my name is Bugs.
单练一下怎么样，娃娃？
You want to play a little one-on-one, doll?
“娃娃？”
"Doll"?
- 乐意奉陪，兔巴哥 - 是的
- On the court, Bugs. - Sure.
她好性感
Ooh. She's hot.
她来了
There she goes.
- 好了吗？ - 是的
- Ready?      - Yes.
我的球
I got it. I got it.
这姑娘有两下子
That girl's got some skills.
什么？
Yes?
再也不许叫我“娃娃”
Don't ever call me "doll."
遵命
Check.
跟你们玩得很开心
Hey, nice playing with you.
挺有本事
Very smooth.
她显然是迷上我了
Ah, she's obviously nuts about me.
看得出来
Obviously.
好吧 球在哪？
Okay. Where's the ball?
开始训练
Let's do some drills.
谁能借我一双球鞋？
Can anyone lend me a pair of sneakers?
球鞋？
Uh, sneakers?
- 对不起    - 哪位能去我家…
- Sorry. - Someone has to go to my house...
- 取我的篮球装备  - 去你家？
- and pick up my basketball gear. - To your house?
- 3维世界的家？ - 是的
- In 3-D land?     - Yeah.
不管你干什么…
Whatever you do...
不要忘了北卡罗莱纳校队的短裤
don't forget my North Carolina shorts.
短裤？大学的短裤？
Your shorts? From college?
我穿在芝加哥公牛队队服里面
I wore them under my Chicago Bulls uniform every game.
比赛后都洗干净
Hey. I washed them after every game.
真的
Sure.
- 我洗过 - 恶心
- I did.    - Gross.
跟在你后面臭死了
The view back here stinks.
什么？
What?
我们就在迈克尔家的前面
We're right in front of Michael's house.
我知道
I knew that.
走这边
Shh. Okay, let's go in this way.
我看还是走那边
I say, let's go in that way.
他总不长记性
He just never learns.
让我想想看
Now, let me see.
肯定差不多，到了
I must be very, very close.
妈呀
Mother.
好漂亮的家
Nice digs.
我看看到底是谁？
Well, well. I wonder who that could be.
一闪，一闪，小星星
Twinkle, twinkle, little star.
他们都在睡觉
Shh. Everyone's sleeping.
- 我知道 - 快点，快点
- I knew that. - Come on, come on.
必须找到迈克尔打球用的东西
We gotta find Michael's basketball stuff.
没有，不在这里
Nope. Nothing in here.
没有 这间餐厅相当不错
Nope. Ah, but a very nice dinette set.
不在这时里
Not here.
去楼上看看
Let's look upstairs.
好吧，不知深浅的家伙
Yes, oh, fearless leader.
他还需要内衣
So he needs his special underwear.
对不起 这女孩的玩具真多
Sorry. You think she's got enough toys?
说起玩具，你知道所有杯子、衬衣和午饭盒子上…
Speaking of toys, you know all those mugs and t-shirts and lunch boxes...
- 都印着我们的画像吗？ - 是的
- with our pictures on them? - Yeah.
你收到过肖像费吗？
You, uh, ever see any money from all that stuff?
- 一分也没有 - 我也没有
- Not a cent. - Me neither.
太不像话了
It's a crying shame.
换个新代理人，我们给人骗了
We gotta get new agents. We're getting screwed.
这是纪念品陈列室
We have found the trophy room.
我们分头去找
Now spread out and search the place.
是，先生 噢，天哪
Yes, sahib. Oh, brother.
我堂堂的大活鸭竟给兔子打下手
Here I am, in the peak of my form playing second banana to some sort of a harebrain.
这个包一定有用
This could be useful. Aha.
工会也不给我做主
If this were a union job, I...
这衬衣不错
That's very nice.
一只鞋子
Oh, one of his shoes.
另一只呢？
Where is that other shoe?
你在哪里？
Where are you?
找到了
Eureka!
乖一点
Come to Papa.
瞧你那双毛脚，笨透了
What a fuzz-foot. You are so clumsy.
- 接着 羽毛头 - 谢谢
- Catch, feather head. - Thanks.
- 该走了  - 没忘记什么吧？
- Well, time to go. - Did we get everything?
- 短裤  - 短裤
- The shorts. - The shorts.
在哪？
In there?
好吧，我去找
Okay, I'll check.
我找到了
I found the shorts.
短裤
The pain.
- 我做你后盾   - 那也不管用
- I'm right behind you, pal. - Uh, that's none too reassuring.
狗乖乖 来根骨头？
Nice puppy. How's about a bone?
- 不行 - 来块火腿怎么样？
- No dice. - What about a nice holiday ham?
- 它不要的 我们谈谈好吗？ - 下去，贝多芬
- He ain't buying it. Can't we talk this over? - Down, Beethoven.
孩子们来了
The kids are here.
给我
Give it to me, Charles.
- 给，兔巴哥 - 谢谢，孩子
- Here you go, Bugs. - Thanks, kid.
坏狗狗 这是我最后一次
Bad dog. That is the last time
跟狗和小孩玩了
I'm ever working with dogs or children.
- 再见拉 - 你们要去哪？
- Bye-bye. - Hey, where you going?
那么你看，我们乐你通将举行一场大型篮球赛…
Well, uh, you see, the Looney Tunes have a big basketball game coming up...
- 还有，你爸爸也参加 - 太好了
- and, uh, your dad's gonna play. - All right.
千万不要告诉任何人
Yeah. But don't tell anybody.
我看到了外星人
I see aliens.
一群来自太空的小生物
Little aliens from outer space.
侵入了你们的体内
They forced their way inside your bodies.
他们需要你们的球技以便在球赛中战胜…
They need your talent to win a basketball game against...
兔巴哥 兔巴哥？
Bugs Bunny. Bugs Bunny?
我还看到了迈克尔・乔丹被吸入高尔夫球洞…
I also see Michael Jordan being sucked down a golf hole...
是毛绒动物
by furry creatures.
- 行了，咱们走吧  - 我们走
- That's it. We're out of here. - We're leaving now.
- 去试试针灸疗法吧 - 好主意 再见
- Let's try some acupuncture. - Good idea. Bye.
我受够了
This is it. This is it.
我不知道你在哪里，迈克尔，但无论你在哪里…
I don't know where you are, Michael, but wherever you are...
你明显觉得在哪儿都比和我在一起好
you obviously enjoy being there more than spending time with me.
希望乔丹没忘了怎么打篮球
You better hope this Jordan character still know how to play hoops.
我也这么想，伙计
You and me both, brother.
给咱们球队起个新名字：
Listen, how is this for a new team name:
鸭之队 别逗了
The Ducks. Please.
就像那个米老鼠们的球队就叫鸭之队吗？
What kind of Mickey Mouse organization would name their team the Ducks?
不行算了 只是个提议
So sue me. It's just a suggestion.
用力做
You're doing it.
就会体型健美
You're becoming mighty.
跟我做 只要苦练，定能减肥
Go! Come on, guys. No pain, no gain.
我没听到 是什么？
I don't hear it. What is it?
- 加油 - 加油
- Come on. - Come on.
- 伙计们？ - 怎么？
- Eh, guys? - Yes?
看看是谁这么精神焕发！
Look who's finally ready to play.
看我还能不能找到感觉
Let's see if I remember how to do this.
漂亮
Nice.
迈克尔！
Michael!
真的是你吗？
Is it really you?
谢天谢地你没出事 我真为你担心
Thank God you're all right. I was so worried.
斯坦，不要这样抱着我
Come on, Stan. Don't hug me, please.
- 对不起 - 你怎么来了？
- Sorry. - What are you doing here?
我要带你回去 你得去练棒球
I gotta take you back. You got baseball practice.
不行，我要帮我的朋友练篮球
I can't. I'm helping my friends in their basketball game.
迈克尔，知不知道你的朋友们都是动画人物？
Michael, you know that your friends are cartoon characters?
那又怎么样？
Yeah. So?
没有烦你，也没有烦我
Doesn't bother you, it doesn't bother me.
让我帮你 让我帮你 我可以帮你
Let me help. Let me help. I can help.
- 你能干什么？ - 那个，你知道的，我…
- What can you do? - Well, you know, I mean...
虽然我个子不高，但我很稳重
I may not be very tall, but I'm slow.
- 块儿大 - 人也傻
- And large. - And a dork.
我干什么都行，迈克尔，任何事
I'll do anything, Michael. Anything.
- 什么都行？ - 什么都行
- Anything?     - Anything.
你过来，来一下
Come here. Come here for a second.
- 坐在这儿 - 好的
- Sit right here. - Okay.
- 好了？ - 好 没问题
- Okay? - Okay. No problem.
太好了，我们一定能赢
All right. All right, let's go, team.
要是有人受伤，我们还有替补
If somebody gets injured, we could see a lot of minutes.
我是啦啦队长
I'm a cheerleader.
（加州英格尔伍德西部大球场）
专员先生，我们已经把这地方密封起来了
Mr. Commissioner, we've got the place sealed off.
安静！女士们先生们，安静！
Quiet! Ladies and gentlemen, please, quiet!
听着 在和各球队老板协商之后，我们决定…
Listen. After meeting with team owners, I have decided...
直至我们能保证NBA球员的健康和安全…
that until we can guarantee the health and safety of our NBA players...
这个赛季不再有篮球比赛了
there will be no more basketball this season.
（今晚世纪篮球大赛）
（主队席）
是的
Yes.
不要挡我的路
Just get out of my way.
（乐你通队）
- 好了？ - 好了！
- Ready?    - Yes!
上场
Let's go.
是头等席吗？
Are these the best seats?
像他们 很好
Like them. Yes.
看得非常清楚，好极了
Can see everything from here. Very good.
- 开始吗？   - 是的，开始
- Ready to go? - Yeah, yeah, sure, sure. Riot.
女士们先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen...
下面介绍乐你通队的出场阵容
the starting lineup for the Tune Squad.
这位是身高2.4英尺，号称南半球奇才的…
Standing 2-foot-4, The Wonder From Down Under...
大嘴怪
the Tazmanian Devil.
担任小前锋的，是身高3英尺2的…
At small forward, standing a scintillating 3-foot-2...
“球队之花”，兔小妹罗拉
The Heartthrob of the Hoops, Lola Bunny.
大前锋，是外号“球场骗子”的达菲鸭
At power forward, The Quackster of the Courts, Daffy Duck.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
真好玩 大家都来嘲笑这个鸭子吧
Very funny. Let's all laugh at the duck.
组织后卫，身高3.3英尺，算上耳朵4英尺…
And at point guard, standing 3-foot-3, 4 feet if you include the ears...
乐你通队的副队长…
co-captain of the Tune Squad...
有乐天派之称的…兔巴哥
The Doctor of Delight, Bugs Bunny.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
下面，乐你通队的教练兼队员…
And now, the player-coach of the Tune Squad...
身高6.6英尺，来自北卡罗莱那…
at 6-foot-6, from North Carolina...
大名鼎鼎的空中飞人，迈克尔・乔丹
His Royal Airness, Michael Jordan.
谁？是乐你通动画吗？
Who? Is he a Looney Tune?
呃… 好像是
Uh... Uh, well, perhaps.
- 你们好了吗？ - 我给他个飞身上篮，杰克
- You guys ready? - I'm set to take it to the rack, Jack.
我要让他们尝尝咱们的厉害
Those Monstars will wish they'd never been born.
伙计们，让我们好好玩一场
Guys, let's just go out and have fun.
参加至尊比赛的挑战者是…
The challengers for the Ultimate Game...
从莫伦山远道而来的：
all the way from Moron Mountain:
魔星队
The Monstars.
加油魔星队！加油魔星队！加油魔星队！
Go Monstars! Go Monstars! Go Monstars!
你在看什么？
What are you looking at?
球鞋不错
Cool shoes.
好了吗？
Ready?
拿到了 拿到了 我拿到球了 我拿到球了
I got it, I got it, I got it. I got the ball. I got the ball.
干得不错，你见过那样的动作吗？
Way to go, boys. Did you see the moves on that one?
来给我露一手 来给我露一手
Come on, show me something. Come on, show me something.
鸭子
The duck.
拦住鸭子
Yeah, beat up on the duck.
天哪
Oh, my.
她没人防守
She was wide open.
注意，接住我的球 小心 小心
Watch it, coming your way. Watch out, watch out.
拦住他
Get him.
（魔星队：06乐你通队：02）
怎么搞的？
How did he do that?
- 投的好，乔先生 - 加油 注意回防
- Nice shot, Mr. J. - Hey, hey, come on. Get back on defense.
干的好！
Way to go!
飞人！飞人！
Air J! Air J!
此路不通
Red light.
- 传给我 传给我 - 传给你？给我吧
- Feed me. Feed me. - Feed you? Feed me.
- 你这傻大猫 - 这球是我的，谢谢
- Bad old putty tat. - I'll take that, thank you.
在家可不要这么干
Don't try this at home.
但愿我身处…
I wish I was in the land of cott...
都给我闪开！
You going somewhere?
我要提醒你，先生
May I remind you, sir,
打人属于很明显违反了规则
that physical violence is patently against the rules.
你是想烤嫩点还是想烤脆点？
Did you order Original Recipe or Extra Crispy?
- 来吧  - 我？
- Let's go. - Me?
我准备好了 我能搞定
Oh, boy. I'm ready. I can do this.
老鼠？你让老鼠上？
The mouse? You picked the mouse?
我喜欢篮球，你喜欢吗？
I love basketball. I always have. Do you?
- 你这么高，一定打得很好 - 是的
- You're big. I bet you're good. - Right.
我个子小，但我练得很刻苦
I'm small, but I'll try hard to be good.
- 好吧 是的 - 真的，我会的 我很努力
- Okay. Yeah. - Really, I will. I always try hard.
妈妈说，“功夫不负有心人…”
My mom says, "Try your best at everything you do..."
你过我一个试试，小妞
Try to get by me, doll.
小妞？
"Doll"?
再不要叫我“娃娃”
Don't ever call me "doll."
- 投的好 - 谢谢，兔巴哥
- Nice shot. - Thanks, Bugs.
嗯？
Hmm?
防守在哪里，小子？我吃定你了
Where's the defense, boy? I got you right here.
911.
馅饼？猪排？还是来点冰水？
Piece of pie? Pork chop? Some sorbet, perhaps?
（场上出现一边倒的局面）
半场时间到
Half-time.
大傻猫
Holy putty tat.
十拿九稳 一切顺利
Yeah, man, we got it going on. One more half.
是的，伙计 我们抓住他们了
Right, man. We got them.
莫伦山，胜利在望了
Moron Mountain, here we come.
我们要做奴隶了
We're gonna be slaves.
加油，伙计们，保持你们的斗志
Come on, guys, keep your head up.
还有半场比赛呢
Got a whole other half to play.
老板来了
It's the boss.
你好，斯沃基先生
Hello, Mr. Swackhammer.
好吧
All right.
上半场打的不错，还要再接再厉
Not bad for the first half, but we gotta keep this up.
没问题 我们偷了…
No problem. We stole...
NBA球员的球技都偷到手了
We stole talent from the best players in the NBA.
来自NBA？
From the NBA.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我闻到了怪味
I smell something.
我们都出了不少臭汗
Uh, we have been playing really hard.
蠢货，不是你们身上
Not you, you idiot.
是从那发出来的
It's coming from over here.
更衣柜
That locker.
看
Look.
是个大胖子
It's the chubby boy.
我闻着他像个间谍
It smells like a spy.
要不要搞公关的？我很能干
You guys need a publicist? I can make you big. Ha, ha.
- 不要灰心 - 给我们讲讲
- I know we're down. - Yeah. Let's hear the story.
我也曾遇到过这种情况
But I've been in this situation many times before.
我们还有赢的希望
We can still win this thing.
比赛还没有结束
It's not over with.
大家要齐心协力
We gotta come together.
我们要相信自己 我们能赢得比赛
We gotta believe in ourselves. We can win this game.
要能那样就好了
Yeah, right. That's gonna help us.
看起来斯坦像是和虫虫特工队刚打完仗
Looks like Stan just had a close encounter with a bug-zapper.
魔星队 魔星队
Monstars. The Monstars.
- 一定很疼 - 没事吧，斯坦？
- That's gotta hurt. - You all right, Stan?
魔星队…
The Monst...
魔星队偷了NBA队员的技术
The Monstars stole the talent from the NBA players.
怪不得这么难对付
So that's what happened to those guys.
我们还是退出比赛吧
I think we should qui... Forfeit.
我既然来了…
I didn't get dragged down here...
就能输给那些丑八怪
just to get my butt whipped by a bunch of ugly Monstars.
我决不答应，不能任凭他们摆布
I ain't going out like that. We're letting them push us around.
我们要反击
We gotta fight them back.
我们要夺回优势
We gotta take it to them.
我们要给他们迎头痛击
We gotta get right in their faces.
怎么样？
What do you say?
同意我的意见吗？
Are you with me or not?
讲完了？非常精彩 你让大家都入迷了
Finished? Great speech and all, doc. You had them riveted.
- 可你是不是忘了什么？ - 什么？
- But, uh, didn't you forget something? - What?
你的秘密武器！
Your secret stuff.
好大的块儿
Whoa, nice deltoids.
小意思
Play along.
你不能独占它 我们是一伙的
Uh, stop hogging it, Mike. We're your teammates.
秘密武器？
Secret stuff?
- 秘密武器？ - 你不是诚心瞒着我们吧？
- Secret stuff? - You wouldn't hold out on us, would you?
不，我认为你们不需要它
No, I mean, I didn't think you guys really needed it.
你们都很健壮 你们都有进取心
I mean, you're so tough. You're competitive.
我们也很胆小，非常需要它
We're also chicken, son. We need it bad.
我也想来点 让我喝一口好吗？
Uh, I'd like some of that. Could I have a sip, please?
这种严重违反卫生条例
You know, this goes against everything they taught me in health class.
还想不想赢球了？
Do you want to win or not?
干杯
Bottoms up.
去打他们个落花流水
How about we go out and kick some alien butt, huh? Let's go.
准备好了吗？预备？
How about it? Ready?
突破
Coming through.
兔巴哥
Bugs.
特快专递
Special delivery.
炸的好
Eh, nice kaboom, Wile E.
让我教训他们
Let's teach them a lesson.
好白屁股
Nice butt.
上来了 你是我的了，笨蛋
Going up. You're mine, fool.
斯拉米
Slammy.
给你们个小惊喜，我的朋友
Hello. A little surprise for you, my friends.
两分
Two points.
真过瘾
This will be good.
好，小鸟
Okay, birdie.
- 好哇！ - 暂停！
- Yes!    - Time out!
住嘴，一边呆着去，都过来
Shut up, you little bug. Get away from me. Powwow.
很好 这段时间打得不错
All right. We're right back in this game.
加油 我们加强防守
Come on, now. Let's play tough defense.
为什么没偷他的技术？
Why didn't you get this guy?
- 他是打棒球的   - 是的，老大，一个棒球手
- He's a baseball player. - Yeah, boss, a baseball player.
我看他像个篮球高手
Looks like a basketball player to me.
我看也是
Yeah, me too.
我要把他弄回莫伦山
He's the one I want for Moron Mountain.
你是在跟我说话吗？
Are you talking to me?
对，我在跟你说话 你想要我吗？过来拿吧
Yeah, I'm talking to you. You want a piece of me? Come and get it.
你有什么条件？
What did you have in mind?
把赌注加大些？
Hat about we raise the stakes a little bit?
有意思
Interesting.
我们赢了，你还NBA队员的球技
If we win, you give the NBA players their talent back.
要是我赢了呢？
But what if we win?
你赢了？
If you win?
我归你
You get me.
太好了
Good deal, boss.
这是个好主意吗？
Doc, you think that's a good ide...?
你会成为我们的王牌明星
You'll be our star attraction.
你会整天不停地签名
You'll sign autographs all day long.
和付了钱的游客打一对一篮球
And play one-on-one with the paying customers.
你必须输
And you'll always lose.
同意吗？
Do we have a deal?
同意
Deal.
好吧
All right.
我认为你不应该这样做
I don't think you should have done that, doc.
我相信我的球队
I have faith in my team.
干掉他们
Crush them.
时机已到
Feeding time, boys.
再见
Goodbye.
闪开
Fore.
妈妈，今天我不想去上学
But, Mommy, I don't want to go to school today.
我想呆在家里帮你烤饼
I want to stay home and bake cookies with you.
- 我在空位，我在空位 - 罗拉，罗拉，注意上面
- I'm open, I'm open. - Lola, Lola, heads up.
泰山压顶
Belly flop.
天哪 兔巴哥！
Oh, my. Bugs!
- 兔巴哥！ - 他是你男朋友？
- Bugs! - Is this your man?
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我？我很好
Me? Oh, yeah. I'm fine.
你呢？
Are you okay?
兔巴哥，谢谢
Oh, Bugs. Thank you.
小事一桩
Aw, it was nothing.
这是最令我感动的一件事
That was the nicest thing anyone's ever done for me.
暂停
Time out.
我本来能当上冠军
I could have been a contender.
魔星
The Monstars. The Monstars.
- 给我来点菜汁… - 妙手回春！
- I could have had a... - Clear!
好了
Okay.
- 还缺一名队员   - 教练，听着
- We need a fifth player. - Hey, coach, listen.
你还有秘密武器吗？
You got any more secret stuff?
我的劲好象下去了
I think it's starting to wear off.
没有下去，那是水
It didn't wear off. It was just water.
秘密武器在自己的心里
You guys had the special stuff inside of you all along.
是啊，我知道，可能不能再给点？
Yeah, yeah, I knew that. But listen, you got any more?
我也想要 也能给我一些吗？
I'll take some. Yeah, uh, can I have some too?
- 斯坦？ - 叫我？
- Stan?      - Me?
你打中锋
You're in at center.
盯住那个庞然大物
Just guard the big guy, okay?
盯住他？我要把他掐死
Guard him? Guard him? I'll smother him.
我就是他身上的一件衣服
I'll be all over him like a cheap suit.
我要像胶一样粘在他身上
I'll be on him like stink on rice.
你就瞧好吧
I tell you, he's going down.
迈克尔，快传给我 给我球 我这没人
Michael, over here. Over here. Over here, I'm open.
太棒了！
Yes!
漂亮的…！
Nice sho...!
真够大的，是不是？
Big man pancake.
快把他弄走
Let's get him out of here.
臭！
Eew.
怎么弄的？
How'd he do that?
这很容易，你也行
Aw, anybody could do that, doc. Even you.
你看
Watch this.
这很简单 这是乐你通的地盘
No sweat. This is Looney Tune Land.
还剩10秒？谢谢你提醒
Ten seconds to go? Thanks for telling me, doc.
我不想报告坏消息，飞人先生
I hate to be the bearer of bad news, Your Airness...
可如果你们凑不够5个人，你们队将输掉比赛
but if you don't find a fifth player, your team will forfeit the game.
- 输掉？ - 正是，飞人先生
- Forfeit? - Precisely, Sir Altitude.
等等，会找到人的
No way. We'll find someone.
我可不知道丹艾克洛德也来卡通世界了
I didn't know Dan Aykroyd was in this picture.
也许我能帮点忙
Perhaps I could be of some assistance.
我们的第5名队员来了
That's our fifth guy.
谢谢，比尔 现在你的梦想就要成真 开始吧
Thanks, Bill. Now you get to live your dream. Let's go.
- 好吧    - 好吧
- All right. - All right.
- 我们要再得两分…   - 我想好了
- We need to score two points... - Here's how I see it.
- 鸭子 - 在
- Duck. - Yes.
把球传给篮下的兔小妹 好吗？
Kick it to the girl bunny down in the post. Yeah?
- 你再把球传给兔巴哥 - 明白了
- You dish it back to the guy bunny. - Got it.
- 把它传给迈克尔 你往篮下跑 - 比尔
- You swing it to Mike. You go to the hole. - Bill.
- 然后扣篮 - 现在我们防守
- And dominate. - We're on defense.
- 是啊 - 哇哦 我可不管防守
- Oh, yeah. - Whoa. I don't play defense.
- 典型想法  - 大家还是听迈克尔的吧
- Typical. - Gonna have to listen to Mike on this.
只要抢到球就传给我
Somebody steal the ball, get it to me
我抓紧最后时间投篮
and I'll score before the time runs out.
一定要有信心
Don't lose that confidence. Okay.
我们来握握手
Paws and wings in here.
天生我才必有用
This is why I was born.
关键时刻显身手
I thrive on pressure.
- 请问，对不起  - 不要随便拽人家的裤子
- Excuse me, uh, sorry. - Yo, yo, easy on the trousers, Daf. Easy.
请原谅，默里先生，有件事我实在不明白
Pardon me. Mr. Murray, something's really been bugging me.
你是怎么来的？
Just how did you get here anyway?
制片人是我朋友，他安排我来的
Producer's a friend of mine. Just had a teamster come and drop me off.
原来如此
Well, that's how it goes.
看见这个大笨熊了吗？
Hey, you see this, uh, kind of chunky fellow over here?
- 就这么办 好的  - 不要让我失望 你这只鸭子
- that's good. Oh, yes. - Let's do it. You the duck.
请遵守比赛规则
Now, let's all play fair. Here.
太空人 打起精神 来吧
Yo, spaceman. Don't choke now. Come on.
该动手了
It's gut-check time.
这球是我的
This must be mine.
球属于我的 我从这边过 我从左边过
This belongs to me. I'm going this way. I'm going left.
别再相信地球人了
Don't ever trust an Earthling.
迈克尔！
Mike!
拦住那姑娘 拦住那姑娘
Get the rabbit. Get the girl.
快点，我这儿是空位
Come on, come on. I'm open.
我是最…！
I'm op...!
- 这是我的 - 做梦
- That's mine. - Not today.
你过不去的，老兄
Hey. Bring it on, dude.
像个娘们
Whoopsie-daisy.
你是我的
You're mine.
给我
Mike, I'm open!
算了吧
Never mind.
乐你通胜
The Tunes win!
传的漂亮
That was a nice pass, man.
你的神臂投篮也够精彩
That was a great stretch for the basket too.
你真的很有进步
You know, you really got some skills.
你可以打NBA比赛了
You might be able to play in the NBA.
谢谢，迈克，承蒙夸奖
Thanks, Mike. I'll probably quote you on that.
我想趁这个机会，激流勇退
But I'm gonna take this opportunity to retire from the game.
- 不要这样 - 不
- No, come on. - No.
我现在就退出篮坛永不复出
No, I'm gonna retire right now. That's all there is to it.
我要保持不败的记录
I'm gonna go out on top, undefeated and untied.
这才明智
That's the way it's gonna be.
- 去庆祝胜利吧 - 你也一起来
- You go celebrate with your team. - Come help us, man.
我很想参加，但我得马上冰敷我的膝盖了，好吗？
I'd like to, but I have to ice down my knees right away, okay?
开始疼得厉害了
They're starting to go.
- 好吧 再见  - 好吧，回见吧
- All right. Goodbye, man. - All right, see you.
- 你确定吗？ - 是的 确定不行，绝对不行
- Are you sure? - Yes. Definitely sure. Definitely.
- 废物 - 对不起
- Losers. - Sorry.
- 成不了气候 - 实在对不起
- Choke artists. - Sorry again.
回到莫伦山再跟你们算帐
Wait till I get you back on Moron Mountain.
一切都完了，回到飞船上去
All right. The party's over. Get in the spaceship.
怎么会这样？
Why do you take it from this guy?
因为他太强了
Because he's bigger.
他很强吗？
He's bigger?
比我们…强
Than we used to be.
你们要干什么？
What are you doing?
- 等等，你们要干什么？ - 过来
- Wait. What are you doing? Wait. - Come here.
你们早就能打败他
Had it in you all the time, didn't you?
- 还有件事 - 把球给我，兔巴哥
- One thing, though. - Pass me the ball, Bugs.
把我朋友们的球技交出来
You gotta give my friends their talent back.
一定要交吗？
Do we have to?
我们有约在先，把手放球上
Yeah, it's part of the deal. Touch the ball.
只好这样了
Oh, okay.
- 很公平的  - 好吧 放上来
- Fair is fair. - There you go. Touch it.
真好玩
That was so much fun.
我觉得自己小的可怜
I feel so insignificant.
衣服太大了
My clothes don't fit.
- 真刺激 - 还有刺激的呢
- What a trip. - I'm up for another one.
能帮个忙吗，兔巴哥先生？
Can we ask you a favor, Mr. Bunny?
我们不想再回莫伦山去了
We don't want to go back to Moron Mountain.
- 我们那里不好 - 糟透了
- We hate it up there. - It stinks.
我们能留下来吗？
Um, I was thinking, could we stay here with you?
求你了
Please.
噢，天哪
Oh, brother.
我不知道你们是否有资格参加乐你通
Eh, I don't know if you guys are looney enough.
乐你通？
Looney enough?
迈克尔，知道现在几点了吗？
Michael, do you know what time it is?
七点十… 七点十… 七点过一刻
Seven-fift... Seven-fift... Quarter past 7.
没错 5分钟后棒球赛就要开始了
Exactly. You've got a baseball game in five minutes.
好的 拿着它
Okay. Take this.
- 没危险？ - 没有，放我包里
- Is it safe? - Yeah, put it in my bag.
走吧
Okay. Let's go.
和你们在一起很愉快
I really enjoyed playing with you guys.
你们有很多…
You guys got a lot of, uh...
- 很多… - 什么？
- A lot of, uh... - Yes?
不管怎么说，这里很有意思
Well, whatever it is, you got a lot of it.
我们走了
All right. Gotta go.
- 兔巴哥 - 迈克尔
- Bugs. - Eh, Mike.
- 不要闯祸   - 我会的
- Stay out of trouble. - You know I will.
过来
Come here.
迈克尔！迈克尔！
We want Michael! We want Michael!
再不来就麻烦了 迈克尔在哪？
The delay is killing us. Where's Michael?
迈克尔在哪？
Where is Michael?
参加另一场比赛还没回来
Oh, he's not back from his other game.
什么比赛？
What other game?
什么另一场比赛？
女士们，先生们…
Ladies and gentlemen...
迈克尔・乔丹
Michael Jordan.
伙计们，我们完了
Guys, we suck.
现在我连我奶奶也不如
Yeah, man. My grandmother plays better than I do.
好歹你们个子高
At least you guys are still tall.
我啥也不是 只是半残的废物
I'm nothing now. Just another short guy.
- 你说的对 - 这是你唯一说得正确的事情
- You got that right. - That's the only thing you got right.
- 谁来了？ - 是谁？
- Who's that? - Who's that?
- 不知道 - 把你们玩得够惨是吗？
- I don't know. - Been getting your butts kicked?
- 他是谁？ - 是迈克
- Who's that? - It's Mike.
- 怎么了？ - 你来这里干嘛？
- What's up? - Why are you here?
用不着难堪 面对现实吧
Don't be embarrassed. Just face it.
你真刻薄
You guys stink.
- 拜托，不要难过  - 我知道
- Come on, Mike. Lighten up. - I know, man.
你想重返赛场吗？
You want your games back, huh?
找回昔日的风光？
What little games you had to begin with.
- 不可能了 - 别说风凉话
- It's hard enough as it is, Mike. - Give us a break.
我帮你们实现它
I'm gonna regret this.
斯坦，把球给我
Stan, give me the ball.
看那个
Look at that.
怎么像是在科幻片里
Looks like something from Star Trek.
- 摸一下 - 算了吧，乔丹
- Touch it. - No way, Jose.
帕特，你想找回球技吗？
Pat, you want your talent back?
你没有选择 摸摸它吧
You don't have any choice. Just touch it.
- 不妨试试 - 不要摸
- I don't know. - Don't touch it.
不然，你们真要永无出头之日了
You're gonna walk around with a bad game for the rest of your career.
摸一下球
Touch the ball.
当心，帕特
Careful, Pat.
我们什么招都试过了
We've tried everything else.
来吧，迈克尔 摸一下
Come on, Charles. Touch it.
还有你们 手放在上面
The rest of you guys. Just touch it.
- 怎么回事？ - 真有意思
- What was that? - I liked that, Mike.
我能拿球了
Hey, I caught it.
看看马格斯的控球
Look at Muggsy handle the rock. Handle it, baby.
我又能打球了
I can handle that rock again.
这才是我熟悉的马格斯
That's the old Muggs I know.
跳投看看
Yeah, get height now.
我的魔力又回到了身上
It gave me my powers back.
不算坏 你们看我的
That wasn't bad. Let me show you something.
- 圆肉球回来了   - 想开开眼界吗？
- The Round Mound is back. - Want to see something?
感觉好极了
Oh, man. That felt good.
- 我好了 - 你好了，伙计
- I got it. - You got it. Yeah, baby.
迈克尔，为何不留下来
Hey, Michael. Why don't you stay,
我们玩个三对三比赛呢？
play some three-on-three with us?
不，恐怕不行
No, I don't think so.
又要去打你的棒球？
You gonna work on that baseball swing?
不要为难棒球手，他不打篮球了
Leave the baseball player alone. He doesn't play basketball anymore.
你的篮球功夫消失了？
He probably doesn't even have it anymore, guys.
迈克尔，听到了？
Michael, do you hear them?
他们说你打不了篮球了
They don't think you can play the game anymore.
只有一件事能证明
There's only one way to find out.
芝加哥公牛队隆重欢迎
The Chicago Bulls welcome back...
迈克尔・乔丹！
Michael Jordan!
（欢迎迈克尔归队）
你又怎么了？
What's the matter, Bill?
我也想像他那样复出
Larry, that could have been me.
你怎么不知好歹，没希望了
Will you get off that kick? It's over. It's done with.
你打不了篮球
You can't play.
好的
Okay.
公牛加油！
Let's go, Bulls.
就到这儿吧，朋友们
Well, that's all, folks.
这是我的台词
That's my line.
走开，让明星说结束语
Step aside, babe. Let a star do this.
就到这…
That's all...
就到这儿吧，朋友们
That's all, folks.
我可以回家了吗？
Can I go home now?
（剧终）